SIBIN BHASKARAN

Houston, TX (346) 971-6333 sibinbhaskaran@gmail.com

https://sibinbhaskaran.github.io/

https://github.com/sibinbhaskaran

Visa status: L2- EAD

Full-Stack Software Engineer

SUMMARY:

Results-oriented software developer with 5+ years of experience and a proven knowledge of field performance, construction management, product development cycles, quality assurance and institutional sales. Committed professional with experience in working globally with diverse cultures.

SKILLS

MS office, JavaScript, jQuery, Node, React,Python,Express, Ajax, MongoDb,Mongoose,HTML,CSS, Bootstrap, Git, Github, Heroku.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING EXPERIENCE:

Software Engineering Immersive student ,May 2020-Aug2020 General Assembly, Houston-Remote

12-week, 500+ hour training program focused in Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, MongoDB, SQL, Python, Flask. Projects done during the immersive.

- BeerDB: App were user can search a beer details and brewery location.-https://sibinbhaskaran.github.io/beerDB-app/index.html
- Car Dealer website/Inventory: Admin can login and feed in the car details of the stock.https://carstoreinventory.herokuapp.com/
- CarrieOKey(Group project): This app allows a user to create a profile, add their favorite Karaoke songs, view the lyrics, and video chat with friends, allowing friends to sing their favorite songs together- https://carrieokey.herokuapp.com/
- Events Finder: User can find events happening near by and post suggestion if any. -https://eventstoactivity.herokuapp.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Project Manager, July 2018 - April 2020 Summit trading and contracting WLL, Doha, Qatar

- Purchase and budgeting of raw materials required for building construction
- Creating quote based on customer budget and materials
- Supervising labors and division of work
- Evaluation of stocks of raw materials on daily basis
- Interacting daily with new and existing clients about work
- Market research on raw materials of different countries

Institutional sales and technical engineer (Quality), Nov 2016 – Jun 2018 MRF LTD, Delhi,India

- Headed quality department of North Zone.
- Verified the product supplied to the customer is in line with quality standards.
- Worked hand to hand with customers for improving or maintaining the quality of the product.
- Addressed on site OEM customer complaints related to quality and service.
- Maintenance and Development of client relations within O.E. Segment Existing and new Clients
- Collection of new product designs from customers, co-ordination with R&D. Appraisal of the product vis-à-vis competitors
- Collection and collation of model wise/manufacturer wise production data, prices for market study & analysis and submission to top management.
- Being actively involved in new developments of different tires with the O.E.M's

Project engineer (Commissioning & planning), Nov 2013 – Oct 2016 Reliance Infra, Mumbai, India

- · Roles and Responsibilities in project- Automated energy meter reading:
 - Configuration of the modems with respect to its desired Energy meter characteristics.
 - Analyzing the nature of faults and rectifying the modems. Manual and automated testing of energy meters and modems.
 - Planning and execution of installation work different towns.
 - Vendor selection, giving seminars and providing them on site training of installation.
 - Handling MIS of installation/survey reports and download reports.
 - Facility management system activity.
 - Providing technical help to on field technicians.

Stock taker, Jun 2012 – Aug 2013 Orridge, Birmingham, UK

- Stock taking accurately for various retail stores (e.g. Zara, pound stores etc.)
- Organizing stock into shelves in both the stockroom and shop floors.
- Storing electronics records of stock count.
- Reporting defective items to supervisors.
- Providing support and assistance to other stockroom /warehouse workers.

Technical support engineer, Jan 2010 – Nov 2010 Sutherland, Chennai, India

- Handling McAfee software customer over the phone.
- Installation of newly purchased software remotely.
- Rectifying customer issues with the software.
- Helping customer over the phone to purchase McAfee antivirus softwares.

EDUCATION

Software engineering-immersive course, General assembly May-Aug 2020 Houston, Tx-Remote

Bachelors in Engineering - Electronics and Communications Engineering 2013

University of Wolverhampton West Midlands, United Kingdom

OTHER INTERESTS

- Played cricket in different zonal levels including University, Organization and region wise. Captained school cricket team and under 15 state cricket team.
- Outdoor sports activity